<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Andrew Moa Blog Site</title>
    <link>https://andrewmoa.site/categories/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Andrew Moa Blog Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>andrew.moa2005@163.com (Andrew Moa)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andrew.moa2005@163.com (Andrew Moa)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Andrew Moa</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 15:47:08 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://andrewmoa.site/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PyCFF - a Python-based curve fitting tool</title>
      <link>https://andrewmoa.site/post/2025-08-25-pycff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>andrew.moa2005@163.com (Andrew Moa)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewmoa.site/post/2025-08-25-pycff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve frequently encountered situations in my work where I need to fit function curves to scattered data. Typical examples include fitting porous media parameters using the pressure drop of a heat exchanger and fitting polynomial density to a fluid medium. While these tasks can be performed using Excel, Origin, and other tools, they are cumbersome and support limited function types. Here, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a simple toolkit in Python that implements function fitting using numpy and scipy. The user interface is written in PySide, allowing for the entire process from input data to output fitting function parameters. The tool also supports data prediction and custom functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabby configuration MSYS2</title>
      <link>https://andrewmoa.site/post/2025-03-26-tabby-setup-msys2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>andrew.moa2005@163.com (Andrew Moa)</author>
      <guid>https://andrewmoa.site/post/2025-03-26-tabby-setup-msys2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tabby.sh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tabby&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; is a very good-looking terminal tool. I first used it to replace the local terminal, and then I found more and more advantages.&#xA;First of all, it has built-in support for SSH connection and SFTP file transfer. The setting operation is simple, avoiding the tedious settings in the Windows terminal. Secondly, it can be used to replace the original Mintty interface of MSYS2 and Cygwin to achieve seamless switching between different terminals.&#xA;Regarding how to call MSYS2 in the Tabby terminal, the following is a record of the configuration method:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
